Guide to the Astor Family Papers 1719-1943 MS 25
New-York Historical Society
Astor family papers
1719-1943
New-York Historical Society
Astor family
MS 25
30.8 Linear feet (34 boxes, 102 volumes, 26 oversize folders)
A collection of documents and bound volumes belonging to the Astor family and its dependents, primarily concerned with their vast real estate holdings in New York City. Includes deeds, leases, mortgages, releases, agreements, receipts, repair orders, surveys, property maps, abstract of titles, ledgers, daybooks, letterbooks, estate statements, and rent rolls.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Arrangement
This collection is organized in two series:
Series I. Property Documents: Leases, Deeds, Mortgages, Maps
Series II. Letterbooks, Daybooks, Rent Rolls, Journals, and Ledgers
Biographical / Historical
For years, the Astor family was the wealthiest family in the world thanks to both the fur trade and real estate market.
The Astor family was established in New York City by John Jacob Astor in 1784. Although Astor bought his first piece of land in 1799, he derived most of his wealth from his American Fur Company (founded in 1808) until the 1830's. At that point, foreseeing the rapid northward expansion of New York City, Astor began to buy and develop large tracts of Manhattan real estate.
His son, William Backhouse Astor, followed in his father's footsteps, and was rumored to know every single inch of land in his possession -- not as farfetched as it sounds, as he kept precise books detailing these properties which can be found in this collection.
The Astor family largely remained in New York, although in 1891, William Waldorf Astor moved his family to Britain, creating an Astor lineage in Europe. Even after moving, William Waldorf Astor kept a close eye on the family's real estate dealings, depending a great deal on correspondence between John Coode-Adams, his London agent, and C.W. Baldwin, his agent in New York. Many of their letters concerning the business transactions of the Astor family are also found in this collection of documents.
The family's land holdings were not limited to New York, and they had properties stretching across the country to Oregon, where there is a city named after the original trading post John Jacob Astor had established in 1811, Astoria, located at the mouth of the Columbia River.
Related Materials
N-YHS holds other papers of William Waldorf Astor within its American Historical Manuscripts Collection (AHMC). See call phrases "AHMC-Astor, William Waldorf papers" and "AHMC-Astor, William Waldorf"
Scope and Contents
This collection spans a time period from 1758-1943 of the Astor family real estate business. It includes deeds, leases, agreements, receipts, work orders, lease renewals, mortgages, ledgers, balances, daybooks, letterbooks (both personal and business), ticklers, and maps of Astor owned properties. Individual documents in boxes are organized alphabetically, and volumes are organized alphabetically by person. Oversize documents are organized in each folder alphabetically by location listed on the document.
Areas of interest in the Astor Family Papers collection:
1. Copy of assignment and lease from Aaron Burr to John Jacob Astor 1803. In an infamous purchase, Astor was able to provide Burr with quick cash he needed after killing Alexander Hamilton.
2. William Backhouse Astor's Letterbook, dated 1852-1855. In a letter addressed to Robert Neilson, London, February 16, 1854, Astor references political unrest in Europe during the time and speculates that should war break out, America would most likely remain a neutral party as it was in its best interest, until other 'Powers' joined in the war and put pressure on the United States. In March, France declared war on Russia, marking the start of the Crimean War. Astor's prediction of US neutrality proved true.
3.William Backhouse Astor's Letterbook, dated 1859-1864. There are two letters addressed to Salmon P. Chase, the Secretary of Treasury in Abraham Lincoln's cabinet, regarding transfer of moneys. (Pages 187 and 278) In a letter to his friend Robert Neilson in November, 1862, Astor makes references to the new form of currency (the 'Greenback') that had been released in April of that year and assures him that the banks would be able to cover this expansion. He also comments that the banks had been the government's principal creditors since the 'rebellion commenced.' Civil War. (Page 270) In another letter to Neilson, Astor comments on the Astor library, still a relatively new institution at the time, encouraging him to return for a visit as there were more volumes than when Neilson had previously visited it.
4. Map Book, dated 1891-1892. Includes newspaper clippings of articles from this time period concerning the Astor family history, John Jacob Astor III, William Waldorf Astor, and the scandal of the false reporting of WW Astor's death.
5. James Madison commission to soldier John Bateman. Includes James Madison's signature from during his tenure as president.
Account books.; Letter books.; Letterpress copybooks.; England.; Germany.; New York (N.Y.); Red Hook (N.Y.); Real estate business -- New York (State) -- New York.; Astor family; Armstrong, John, 1758-1843; Astor, Henry, 1754-1833; Astor, John Jacob, 1763-1848; Astor, John Jacob, 1822-1890; Astor, John Jacob, 1886-1971; Astor, Waldorf Astor, Viscount, 1879-1952; Astor, William B. (William Backhouse), 1792-1875; Astor, William Waldorf, Viscount, 1848-1919; Baldwin, C. W.; Coode-Adams, John; Ogden, Nicholas Gouverneur, 1776-1823; Ogden, Samuel G. (Samuel Gouverneur), 1779-1860
- Series I: Property Documents: Leases, Deeds, Mortgages, Maps, 1758-1940
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains individual documents spanning from 1758-1940 and pertaining to Astor owned properties, including title abstracts, deeds, leases, mortgages, agreements, and notification of arrears. It also contains documents related to the various branch families of the Astors, including the Wards, the Langdons, the Chanlers and so forth. Not only are there assignments of properties in these folders, but also marriage agreements, receipts, word orders, and Supreme Court cases due to complaints leveled against the John Jacob Astor Estate.
  - Subseries I.1: Aaron Burr to Bills for Properties, 1784-1916
    - Aaron Burr, 1803 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 1)
      Copy of assignment and lease from Aaron Burr to John Jacob Astor- 1803 Includes two signatures belonging to Aaron Burr, although one is redacted on the copy of the canceled lease. John Jacob Astor employed many different techniques in making money from real-estate, including 'lending' money to landowners. One of the infamous deals made was lending money to his friend Aaron Burr who needed quick cash to flee the country after shooting and killing Alexander Hamilton. In return, Aaron Burr turned over the lease to his tract of land, what is now Greenwich Village, which was to become a huge source of income for John Jacob.
    - Ann Street, 1830 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Assessment of Properties, n.d. (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Assignment of Leases, 1812-1831 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Astor Building, 1879-1916 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Astor Building, 1879-1916 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Astor House, 1784-1880 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Astor House, 1784-1880 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Avenue A, 1834-1853 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bank Agreements, 1838 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Barclay Street, 1843 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bayard Family, 1800-1832 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bentzon Family, 1819 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 13)
      Magdalen Astor, John Jacob Astor's daughter, married Adrian Bentzon, but soon divorced him on grounds of infidelity on his part. This file contains an assignment of a bond after the divorce and remarriage of Magdalen to John Bristed, signing it over from Bentzon to Magdalen.
    - Bills for Properties, 1842-1849 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Subseries I.2: Bills of Estate to Bowery Street, 1804-1911
    - Bills of Estate, 1824-1843 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bills of Estate, 1824-1843 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Bills of Estate, 1824-1843 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bills of Estate, 1824-1843 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bills of Estate, 1824-1843 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bills of Estate, 1824-1843 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bloomingdale Road, 1824-1847 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bonds, 1821-1911 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Boreel Trustees, 1838-1876 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Boreel Trustees, 1838-1876 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bowery Street, 1804-1868 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I.3: Bowery Street to Broadway, 1804-1922
    - Bowery Street, 1804-1868 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bowery Street, 1804-1868 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bowery Street, 1804-1868 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bowery Street, 1804-1868 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bristed Family, 1832-1874 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3, Folder 5)
      Biographical / Historical
      After divorcing Adrian Bentzon, Magdalen Astor married Reverend John Bristed, an English gentleman, and gave birth to John Jacob Astor's first grandson, Charles Astor Bristed.
    - Broadway, 1804-1922 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Broadway, 1804-1922 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Subseries I.4: Broadway to Charlton Street, 1804-1922
    - Broadway, 1804-1922 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Broadway, 1804-1922 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Broadway, 1804-1922 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Broadway, 1804-1922 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Broome Street, 1811-1897 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Broome Street, 1811-1897 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Budd Street, 1806-1811 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Carey Family, 1876-1882 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Chanler Family, 1862-1882 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Charlton Street, 1808-1864 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4, Folder 10)
  - SubseriesI.5: Chatham Row to Dayton's Triangle, 1819-1896
    - Chatham Row, 1828 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Chenango County, 1819-1844 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Cherry Street, 1840 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 3)
    - City Hotel, 1828-1846 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Cozine Farm, 1830-1876 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 5)
      Land owned by the Trinity Church Corporation which was highly contested by the family tracing their ancestry to the original owner, Anneke Jans Bogardus. However, the Church still sold off pieces of the property, including selling to the Astor family. Abstract of titles, deeds, leases, and mortgages from those and other transactions concerning the Cozine Farm properties can be found here.
    - Cozine Farm, 1830-1876 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Cozine Farm, 1830-1876 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Cozine Farm, 1830-1876 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Cozine Farm, 1830-1876 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Cozine Farm, 1830-1876 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Crown Point Iron Company, 1895-1896 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Cruger's Wharf, 1849 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Dayton's Triangle, 1826-1837 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Subseries I.6: Delano Family to Eden Farm, 1803-1911
    - Delano Family, 1830-1901 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Delano Family, 1830-1901 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 2)
    - De Nottbeck, 1839-1876 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 3)
      John Jacob Astor's granddaughter, Cecilia Langdon, married Jean De Nottbeck in 1849. Soon after, she and her husband petitioned a complaint against the executors of John Jacob Astor's Estate, saying that she was owed $100,000 as described in the will of the late Astor. The complaint and appeal were brought before the Supreme Court, and the responses and replies can be found in this folder.
    - De Nottbeck, 1839-1876 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 4)
    - DeStuers, 1875-1882 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Dey Street, 1851-1890 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Dutchess County, 1810-1823 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I.7: Eden Farm, 1803-1911
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Eden Farm, 1803-1911 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Subseries I.8: Ehninger Family to Grand Street, 1819-1915
    - Ehninger Family, 1819-1851 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Eighth Avenue, 1830-1889 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Elizabeth Street, 1828-1831 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Eleventh Avenue, 1864 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Elmwood Park, 1861-1915 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Elmwood Park, 1861-1915 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Fifth Avenue, 1845-1875 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 7)
    - First Avenue, 1834-1836 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 8)
    - First Street, 1856 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Florida, 1828 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Forty Seventh Avenue, 1866 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Fourth Avenue, 1832-1856 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Fourth Street, 1845 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Gillespie, Moffat and Company, 1831-1869 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Grand Street, 1832-1846 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Subseries I.9: Greenwich Lane to Hudson Street, 1797-1876
    - Greenwich Lane, 1797-1835 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Greenwich Lane, 1797-1835 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Greenwich Street, 1810-1865 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Greenwich Street, 1810-1865 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Hamersley Street, 1825-1846 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Hamilton Flats, 1890 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Hart Estate, 1816-1832 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Hermitage, The, 1829-1830 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Hetty Street, 1808-1817 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 9)
    - "H" Lots on 136th Street, 1860-1863 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Hottinguer and Company, 1858-1876 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Hudson Street, 1825-1844 (Offsite-box 9, Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Subseries I.10: Individual Companies to King Street, 1816-1931
    - Individual Companies, 1840-1884 (Offsite-box 10, Box 10, Folder 1)
    - John Jacob Astor I, 1816-1931 (Offsite-box 10, Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kane Family, 1857-1895 (Offsite-box 10, Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kane Family, 1857-1895 (Offsite-box 10, Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Kane Family, 1857-1895 (Offsite-box 10, Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Kane Family, 1857-1895 (Offsite-box 10, Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Kane Family, 1857-1895 (Offsite-box 10, Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Kane Family, 1857-1895 (Offsite-box 10, Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Kane Family, 1857-1895 (Offsite-box 10, Box 10, Folder 9)
    - King Street, 1825-1844 (Offsite-box 10, Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Subseries I.11: Lafayette Place to Langdon Family, 1808-1887
    - Lafayette Place, 1808-1887 (Offsite-box 11, Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Lafayette Place, 1808-1887 (Offsite-box 11, Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Langdon Family, 1848-1882 (Offsite-box 11, Box 11, Folder 3)
      Dorothea married Colonel Walter Langdon (against her father's express wishes as the dashing young Colonel had no money—however, after a period of estrangement, John Jacob and his daughter were reunited and the Langdons moved into the property known as Hyde Park, which was owned by none other than John Jacob himself) and gave birth to eight children, creating a line of 'Langdon Children' as they are labeled in property and estate documents.
    - Langdon Family, 1848-1882 (Offsite-box 11, Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Langdon Family, 1848-1882 (Offsite-box 11, Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Langdon Family, 1848-1882 (Offsite-box 11, Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Langdon Family, 1848-1882 (Offsite-box 11, Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Langdon Family, 1848-1882 (Offsite-box 11, Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Langdon Family, 1848-1882 (Offsite-box 11, Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Subseries I.12: Langdon Family to Morrisania Avenue, 1807-1924
    - Langdon Family, 1848-1882 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Langdon Family, 1848-1882 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Langdon Family, 1848-1882 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Leroy Street, 1830-1833 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 4)
    - List of Deeds, 1807-1879 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Ludlow Street, 1846-1858 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Madison Avenue, 1848-1924 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Madison Avenue, 1848-1924 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Michigan, 1836-1845 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1828-1928 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Monroe Street, 1826-1834 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Morrisania Avenue, 1887 (Offsite-box 12, Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Subseries I.13: Mount Morris Square to One Hundred Streets, 1792-1932
    - Mount Morris Square, 1857-1902 (Offsite-box 13, Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Murray Hill, 1805-1922 (Offsite-box 13, Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Murray Hill, 1805-1922 (Offsite-box 13, Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Nassau Street, 1837-1859 (Offsite-box 13, Box 13, Folder 4)
    - New Jersey, 1792-1806 (Offsite-box 13, Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Newport, Rhode Island, 1809-1929 (Offsite-box 13, Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Ninth Avenue, 1835-1860 (Offsite-box 13, Box 13, Folder 8)
    - One Hundred Streets, 1877-1932 (Offsite-box 13, Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Subseries I.14: One Hundred Streets to Property Taxes, 1826-1880
    - One Hundred Streets, 1877-1932 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 1)
    - One Hundred Streets, 1877-1932 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Orchard Lane, 1826-1866 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Oswego County, 1836-1848 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Park Theatre, 1828-1842 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Pearl Street, 1827 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Powers of Attorney, 1819-1880 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Powers of Attorney, 1819-1880 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Powers of Attorney, 1819-1880 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Powers of Attorney, 1819-1880 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Powers of Attorney, 1819-1880 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Prince Street, 1836-1838 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Property Taxes, 1835-1890 (Offsite-box 14, Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Subseries I.15: Rivington Street to Twenty First Street, 1818-1940
    - Rivington Street, 1847 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Rope Walk, 1822 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Rumpff Family, 1834-1872 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Second Street, 1826-1874 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Seventh Avenue, 1846 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Sixth Avenue, 1856 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Spring Street, 1825-1848 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 7)
    - State Street, 1818-1824 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Tenth Avenue, 1830-1882 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Third Avenue, 1835-1872 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Town of Westchester, 1833-1940 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Town of Westchester, 1833-1940 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Trinity Church, 1847 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Twelfth Street, 1851-1877 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Twenty First Street, 1830-1851 (Offsite-box 15, Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Subseries I.16: Union Place to Ward Family, 1812-1881
    - Union Place, 1836 (Offsite-box 16, Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Utica, 1841-1842 (Offsite-box 16, Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Vandam Street, 1812-1844 (Offsite-box 16, Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Vandam Street, 1812-1844 (Offsite-box 16, Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Varick Street, 1822-1840 (Offsite-box 16, Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Vesey Street, 1826-1840 (Offsite-box 16, Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Ward Family, 1838-1881 (Offsite-box 16, Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Ward Family, 1838-1881 (Offsite-box 16, Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Ward Family, 1838-1881 (Offsite-box 16, Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Ward Family, 1838-1881 (Offsite-box 16, Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Subseries I.17: Ward Family to Written Agreements, 1802-1905
    - Ward Family, 1838-1881 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Ward Family, 1838-1881 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Warren Street, 1838-1863 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Washington Street, 1824-1846 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Water Street, 1802-1849 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 5)
    - West End Avenue, 1905 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 6)
    - West Street, 1825-1830 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Wilks Trust, 1841-1879 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 8)
    - William Backhouse Astor, 1835-1876 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 9)
      Miscellaneous pertaining to William Backhouse Astor.
    - Wisconsin, 1853 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Written Agreements, 1830-1836 (Offsite-box 17, Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I.18: Henry Astor Estate, 1785-1873
    Biographhical/Historical
    Henry Astor was John Jacob Astor's older brother, and had moved to the Americas years before and owned a butcher's shop in Fulton Market on Bowery Street. Henry was actually the first Astor to look to real estate for profit, investing the money earned from his business into land, which he later urged John Jacob to do when his younger brother began making a comfortable living for himself. He and his wife Dorothea were childless and happily took the young man in. When Henry passed away, he left the control of his estate to John Jacob and are included in the Astor Family Papers.
    - Henry Astor Estate, 1785-1873 (Offsite-box 18, Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Henry Astor Estate, 1785-1873 (Offsite-box 18, Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Henry Astor Estate, 1785-1873 (Offsite-box 18, Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Henry Astor Estate, 1785-1873 (Offsite-box 18, Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Henry Astor Estate, 1785-1873 (Offsite-box 18, Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Henry Astor Estate, 1785-1873 (Offsite-box 18, Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Subseries I.19: Adams-Baldwin Letters, 1890-1895
    - Adams-Baldwin Letters, 1890-1891 (Offsite-box 19, Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Adams-Baldwin Letters, 1891 (Offsite-box 19, Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Adams-Baldwin Letters, 1892 (Offsite-box 19, Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Adams-Baldwin Letters, 1892 (Offsite-box 19, Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Adams-Baldwin Letters, 1893 (Offsite-box 19, Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Adams-Baldwin Letters, 1894 (Offsite-box 19, Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Adams-Baldwin Letters, 1894 (Offsite-box 19, Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Adams-Baldwin Letters, 1895 (Offsite-box 19, Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Adams-Baldwin Letters, 1895 (Offsite-box 19, Box 19, Folder 9)